

Name:

Balmukund

Sahu

Address: Thane

Phone: +919833220536

Email id: Balmukundsahu91@gmail.com

DOB: 13 February 1995

Gender: Male

LinkedIn profile: https://www.linkedin.com/in/camukund

AWARDS AND EXTRA CURRICULLAM ACTIVITIES

- **1.** Awarded with "KUDOS" by BSR and CoLLP for performance during FY 2022-23
- 2. Awarded with "Rating 2" for overall performance of FY 2022-23 by B S R and Co HP
- 3. Awarded with "A" Grade in **Practical Training Assessment Test** conducted by ICAI

CA. Balmukund R Sahu

Having started my professional career into Statutory Audit, I have worked for various industries with B S R and Co. LLP (an affiliates of KPMG India), prominently into Real Estate and construction and Service Sector such as Cash Replacement Agency, Information Management Service. As an articled assistant, I have enriching experience in Statutory Audit, Taxation (Direct and International Taxation) and Corporate Compliance. I am best at Managment and leadership, problem solving, delivering quality output within time, client commitment and possess best interpersonal skills.

Work Experience

October 2021 - Present

Senior Executive at KPMG India, Mumbai

Majorly worked for Construction and Real Estate Industries and Service Sector

Construction and Real Estate Industries: - Being Key member of AET to Audit one of Giant listed company having consolidated turnover of Rs. 2250 Crores. Excellent exposure of various Revenue model such as Revenue Share, Profit Share, Slum-Rehabilitation Development (SRA) and Joint Development Agreement (JDA) under Real Estate and construction Industries. Involve in Planning and execution of audit as Incharge. Thorough review of the Plan documents and amendments thereof. Application of plan provisions in performing Test of control (Including Identification of General IT Control and Control Activity and mapping the GITC with relevant Risk arising from IT (RAFIT)) and substantive procedures on various testworks of Revenue Recognition, Procurement to Pay, JE Testing, Investment held by company and Related Party Transaction. Performed procedures to ensured compliance with CARO 2016. Reviewing the work of team members and providing constructive feedback on the same

Performed quarterly Limited Review of financial presentation as per SEBI (LODR), IND AS and Companies Act 2013. Performed Audit of IFRS Financial for consolidated purpose (Conversion of IND As to IFRS). And Also Led RERA audit of 10 projects based in Mumbai and Bangalore

Service Sector (Agency and Professional Services): - Being Incharge of AET to Audit one of Pvt. company having consolidated turnover Aprox of Rs. 1200 Crores. Excellent exposure of revenue model of Service sector business such as Cash Replacement Agency, Cash-in-Transit Services, Dedicated Cash Van Services, Managed Service Provider, and Information Management Services.

Performed Audit of Ind AS Transition from IGAAP as company first time adopted Ind As based on the turnover. Ind AS Transition Analysis of Revenue from Operation, Trade Receivable, DTA/DTL, and Leases.

Used followings audit tools in course of Audit

- 1. KPMG Clara Workflow
- 2. E-Audit
- **3.** SAP
- 4. Tally ERP 9
- 5. Data Snipper
- 6. MS Office

November 2019 to December 2020

Team Leader in Tax and Account at Nirhali Consultancy Services, Thane

Audit & Financial Reporting

- Led a team of 5 members for **certifications, tax audits, and Preparation of financial** statements of corporate and non-corporate clients in 5+ sectors, including agency of Bharat Petroleum corporation limited
- Analyzed Financial statement for carrying out **Statutory Audit of Company**
- Preparation of Financial statement as per SCH III of Companies Act, 2013.

Taxation

- Handled Various **GST assignments** relating to **Advisory & Compliances**, including **tax payments & refunds** of clients involved in different lines of businesses. Assisted in refunds issues of Export of services without payment of tax.
- Handled Various Income Tax assignments relating to Corporate as well as non- corporate tax compliance, Tax Audit, return filling

June 2016 to June 2019

Articled Assistant at Vinay Lad & Company, Thane

Financial Reporting

- -Assisted in preparation of **standalone financial statement as well as consolidated financial statement**
- Prepared and analyzed **projected financial statement of 5 year and drafted projected financial report**

<u>Audit</u>

- Led a team while conducting **audit** of **Head Office as well as Branch** of company engaged AC Maintenance
- Performed procedure to ensured compliance with CARO, 2016
- Assisted in **statutory audit as well as drafted audit report** of company which are engaged in Human Resource and Recruitment, Government contract, Manufacturing Company, Retail Industry, Electricity supply company

MCAServices

Handled Various **ROC** assignments relating to Incorporation of Company, Filling financial statement (AOC-4) and Annual return (MGT-7), Appointment and Resignation of Director, DIN Services and other annual ROC compliances such as Form-DPT3 and DIR-3 KYC

Income Tax

- -Handled various assignments relating to preparation and filling of returns of individuals, partnerships & companies, TDS compliance, Tax planning of corporate and non-corporate entities, Tax Audit
- Assisted in assessment before Income Tax authority
- Engaged into advisory of International Taxation in relation to DTAA
- Specific form under Income Tax e.g., Form 67, SFT, Form 15CA, Form 15CB

Education and Qualification:

November 2016- July 2021 Chartered Accountant (ICAI)
Financial Year 2015 to 2016 Master of Commerce (R J College Ghatkopar)
Financial Year 2012 to 2015 Bachelor of Commerce (R J College Ghatkopar)